Finding Aid for Michigan municipal charters
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Michigan municipal charters
1913-1962
Michigan Historical Collections (collector)
94164 Cc 2
Municipal charters of various Michigan cities, some include amendments.
1 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Most of the collection was donated by C. F. Norton (donor 1862 ), with some other items added.
The collection is open without restriction.
The Michigan Municipal Charters collections was brought together by the Michigan Historical Collections from a variety of sources and accessions, principally from a donation by C. F. Norton.
Municipal charters of various Michigan cities, some include amendments. Some charters are cataloged separately in the MHC printed works catalog.
Subjects:
Alpena (Mich.)--Charters.; Ann Arbor (Mich.)--Charters.; Battle Creek (Mich.)--Charters.; Benton Harbor (Mich.)--Charters.; Birmingham (Mich.)--Charters.; Cadillac (Mich.)--Charters.; Dearborn (Mich.)--Charters.; Detroit (Mich.)--Charters.; East Ann Arbor (Ann Arbor, Mich.)--Charters.; Eastpointe (Mich.)--Charters.; East Lansing (Mich.)--Charters.; Gaylord (Mich.)--Charters.; Grosse Pointe Woods (Mich.)--Charters.; Hazel Park (Mich.)--Charters.; Holland (Mich.)--Charters.; Inkster (Mich.)--Charters.; Jackson (Mich.)--Charters.; Kalamazoo (Mich.)--Charters.; Ludington (Mich.)--Charters.; Marquette (Mich.)--Charters.; Midland (Mich.)--Charters.; Monroe (Mich.)--Charters.; Mount Clemens (Mich.)--Charters.; Mount Pleasant (Mich.)--Charters.; Muskegon (Mich.)--Charters.; Muskegon Heights (Mich.)--Charters.; Parchment (Mich.)--Charters.; Petoskey (Mich.)--Charters.; Pontiac (Mich.)--Charters.; Reed City (Mich.)--Charters.; Rochester (Mich.)--Charters.; Roosevelt Park (Mich.)--Charters.; Royal Oak (Mich.)--Charters.; Saginaw (Mich.)--Charters.; Saint Clair Shores (Mich.)--Charters.; Sault Sainte Marie (Mich.)--Charters.; Scottville (Mich.)--Charters.; South Haven (Mich.)--Charters.; Tecumseh (Mich.)--Charters.; Traverse City (Mich.)--Charters.; Troy (Mich.)--Charters.; Walled Lake (Mich.)--Charters.; Warren (Mich.)--Charters.; Wyoming (Mich.)--Charters.; Ypsilanti (Mich.)--Charters.
- Charters
  - Alpena, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Battle Creek, proposed, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Benton Harbor amended to 1945, 1921 (Box 1)
    Amendments to 1954 attached.
  - Birmingham, 1933. Amendments to attached, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Cadillac, 1913 (Box 1)
  - Dearborn, 1942 (Box 1)
  - Dearborn 1942 amended to 1957, 1942-1957 (Box 1)
  - Detroit amended to 1944, 1918 (Box 1)
    Amendments to 1945 attached.
  - East Ann Arbor, proposed, 1946 (Box 1)
  - East Detroit, 1929. Amendments to attached, 1958 (Box 1)
  - East Lansing, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Gaylord, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Grosse Pointe Woods, proposed, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Grosse Pointe Woods, 1950. Amendments to attached, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Hazel Park, 1942. Amendments to attached, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Hol, 1913 (Box 1)
  - Holland, 1950. Amendments to attached, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Inkster, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Jackson amended to 1952, 1914 (Box 1)
    Amendments to 1961 attached.
  - Kalamazoo 1918 amended to 1941, 1918-1941 (Box 1)
  - Kalamazoo amended to 1955, 1918 (Box 1)
    Amendments to 1959 attached.
  - Ludington 1916 printed 1928, 1916-1928 (Box 1)
  - Marquette, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Midland 1944 reprinted 1961, 1944-1961 (Box 1)
  - Monroe, 1913 (Box 1)
  - Mount Clemens, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Mount Pleasant 1921 amended to 1954, 1921-1954 (Box 1)
  - Muskegon 1919 amended to 1951, 1919-1951 (Box 1)
  - Muskegon Heights 1922 amended to 1955, 1922-1955 (Box 1)
  - Parchment, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Petoskey, 1924. Amendments to attached, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Pontiac amended to 1958, 1920 (Box 1)
    Amendments to 1950 attached.
  - Reed City, 1957 (Box 1)
  - Rochester, 1948 (Box 1)
  - Roosevelt Park, 1946 (Box 1)
  - Royal Oak 1921 amended to 1957, 1921-1957 (Box 1)
  - Saginaw amended to 1953, 1936 (Box 1)
    Amendments to 1960 attached.
  - St. Clair Shores, 1950 (Box 1)
  - Sault Ste. Marie, 1952. Amendments to attached, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Scottville, 1958 (Box 1)
  - South Haven, proposed, 1955 (Box 1)
  - South Haven, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Tecumseh, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Traverse City 1940 amended to 1955, 1940-1955 (Box 1)
  - Troy, 1955. Amendments to attached, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Walled Lake, 1954 (Box 1)
  - Warren, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Wyoming, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Ypsilanti, 1947. Amendments to attached, 1960 (Box 1)